Ammar Almajed

Software Engineer

💌 ammaralmajed7@gmail.com 📞 +966542463848 👂 Dhahran/Saudi Arabia

OBJECTIVE

As a Software Engineer experienced in the full software development life cycle, I excel in writing requirements, designing architectures, development, testing, deployment, and maintenance processes. My proficiency in Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) and a strong commitment to software quality measurements enable me to deliver high-performing and scalable software solutions that meet project standards and expectations.

EDUCATION

King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals

Aug 2019 - May 2024 | Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Bachelor of Science: Software Engineering

Cumulative GPA: 3.77 / 4.00 with First Honors.

EXPERIENCE

Student Assistant

May 2023 – Jul 2023 | Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals - KFUPM

Helping Students in Math 208 (Differential Equations & Linear Algebra)

Exchange Student

Aug 2022 – Dec 2022 | Daejeon, South Korea

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology

Elected to represent KFUPM in the exchange program which was held in KAIST between August 2022 to December 2022.

Introduction to Programming in Python Grader

Jun 2020 – Aug 2020 | Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals - KFUPM

Correcting python and C programming assignments for more than 500 students.

PROJECTS

CarGAN Aug 2023 - Dec 2023

PvTorch

Developed a model that generate accurate car images using GAN architecture, with discriminator loss equal to

Benchmarking Aug 2023 - Dec 2023

Sklearn | Tensorflow | PvTorch

Develop diverse models, including SVM, NN, DT, and XGB on a dataset to measure each model performance and selecting the best model with 94% accuracy. In addition, develop an active learning mechanism that enabled the model to achieve similar levels of accuracy with less amount of data.

SKILLS LANGUAGES

Technical Skills

• Web Development:

Backend: Django | Express

Frontend: Vanilla JS | AngularJS

- Deep Learning: PyTorch
- Virtualization: Docker
- Version control: Git
- Data science: Pandas | Matplotlib
- Programming Languages: Python | JavaScript |

Arabic

English

TOEFL 74